

Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

# Mr B. Kumar

**NATIONALITY**: Indian

#### **SUMMARY**

Engineering Services mainly projects, utilities (Water, Compressed Air, Steam, Power, Humidification & Air Conditioning) & Maintenance of large operation & backed by Engineering, Product Manufacturing, Machinery Fabrication, Plant and Machinery Erection, Commissioning and Maintenance of them have been my strong experiences in reputed companies. Apart from these I have been involved in Environmental Control for large Textile Industries. With the background of Engineering qualification, Marketing Management and various computer application along with quality and environmental certificates it would be most suitable for me to have senior most Engineering position in any industrial sector and anywhere in India or Abroad

## **EDUCATION**

- BE (Mech.) from BMS College of Engineering, Bangalore with First Class.
- PGDMM (Post Graduation in Marketing Management) from IGNOU, New Delhi.
- AutoCAD 2004 in Mechanical from CAD Centre, Ahmedabad.

#### **EMPLOYMENT RECORD**

#### **Engineering Manager**

Ashima Textile, Ahmedabad

(Utilities & Environment Control)

(1997 to 2004)

Appointed in 1997 as Assistant Manager (Engineering) and assigned to look after utilities and maintenance of Air Compressors, Blowers, Boilers, DG sets, CPP, RO Plant, Water Softening Plant, Humidification Plants, Effluent Treatment Plants. For my wonderful performance I was promoted to Manager (Engineering and Environment Control) in 1998. I was given the additional responsibilities of Environment Control of Group Ashima. I successfully maintained the Pollution Board norms by proper operation of Effluent Treatment Plants and Boilers. Granted all the consents by GPCB & AMC to run the industry by my operation, maintenance and liaisioning skills.



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Engineer

Larsen & Toubro Limited.

(Planning)

(1995 to 1997)

Looking after for the planning, procurement and execution of CCM-BSL Modernization. Fabrication of Light and Technological Structures, Erection of Structures and Engineering Equipment and Commissioning of Continuous Casting Machine and Steel Refining Unit at Bokaro Steel Plant.

Engineer

G.I.B. Pvt. Ltd., Jamshedpur

(Production)

(1994 to 1995)

Fabrication of Technological structures and erection of structures and equipments for Reheating- furnace in TISCO, Jamshedpur.

Engineer

(Mechanical)

**Kinetic Engineering, BS City** 

(1993 to 1994)

Fabrication and Erection of light structures.

Engineer

MMT Ltd., Hyderabad.

(Sales) (1991 to 1993)

Planning Marketing Strategies, Exploring New Markets, Market Research, Coordinating Sales Services.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **TRAINING & SEMINARS**

- "Operation & Maintenance of Centrifugal Air Compressor (CENTAC)", by INGEROSOLLRAND, Ahmedabad.
- "Waste Water Management by ION Exchange (I) Ltd., Mumbai.
- ISO 9001: 2000, ISO 14001 Training by EQMS New Delhi, BVQI and Amana Limited Switzerland.
- Managerial Skill Development by ATIRA, Ahmedabad.
- Workshop on Industrial Water Management by EA Water, New Delhi.